# Germain Vallverdu

# Associate Professor -- PhD in Chemical Physics



10 août 1983, France Maried, 2 children

#### **Contact**

germain.vallverdu@univ-pau.fr (33) 5 59 40 78 51 (33) 6 88 59 08 87

> IPREM Technopôle Hélioparc 2 ave du Président P. Angot FR-64053 Pau cedex 9

### **Theoretical Chemistry**

Computational strategy
Development
Surfaces, interfaces
VASP, CRYSTAL (solid)
Gaussian (molecule)
DL-POLY, AMBER (dynamic)

### **Programmation**

Fortran, C Python LATEX, HTML/CSS

#### Languages

French English (Professional)

#### On the web

orcid.org/0000-0003-1116-8776 •• gVallverdu •• gvallver.perso.univ-pau.fr

#### **Abstract**

Assistant professor at the Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour, I am a theoretical chemist at IPREM institute (Institute for Analytical sciences and chemical physics applied to environment and materials). My research activities concern the development of new methods and computational strategies at different time or space scales, applied to the investigations of complex systems. I teach mainly chemical-physics subjects at the UFR sciences et techniques de Pau.

## **Experience Professionnelle**

since 2010 Université de Pau et des Pays de l'Adour

Pau, France

Associate professor

Theoretical chemistry and computational approaches. Surfaces, interfaces and reactivity.

2009-2010 CEA - DAM

Bruyères le châtel, France

Université Paris-Sud 11

Postdoctoral position

2006-2009 **PhD in chemistry** speciality theoretical chemistry

Development and implementation of mesoscopic models for reactive shock waves propagation in heterogeneous systems.

2006-2009 Université Paris-Sud 11

Orsay, France

PhD Student

Theoretical study of photophysical processes in fluorescent proteins.

### **Formation**

	Mention très honorable	
2004-2006	<b>Master degree of chemistry</b> speciality molecular chemical-physics Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2004	<b>Bachelor Degree of chemical-physics</b> Mention TB	Université Paris-Sud 11
2003-2006	Magistère de Physico-Chimie Moléculaire	Université Paris-Sud 11 - ENS Cachan
2001-2003	Undergraduate physics and chemistry	Lycée François Arago, Perpignan

# **Main publications**

Vallverdu, G.; Minvielle, M.; Andreu, N.; Gonbeau, D.; Baraille, I. Surface Science **2016**, 649, 46–55.

Guille, E.; Vallverdu, G.; Tison, Y.; Bégué, D.; Baraille, I. The Journal of Physical Chemistry C **2015**, 119, 23379–23387.

Guille, E.; Vallverdu, G.; Baraille, I. The Journal of Chemical Physics 2014, 141, 244703.

Martin, L.; Vallverdu, G.; Martinez, H.; Cras, F. L.; Baraille, I. Journal of Materials Chemistry **2012**, 22, 22063–22071.

Maillet, J. B.; Bourasseau, E.; Desbiens, N.; Vallverdu, G.; Stoltz, G. Europhysics Letters **2011**, 96, 68007.

Vallverdu, G.; Demachy, I.; Mérola, F.; Pasquier, H.; Ridard, J.; Lévy, B. Proteins: Structure, Function, and Bioinformatics **2010**, 78, 1040–1054.